# Zhitong Gao

□ (+86) 152-7101-6929 | @ gaozht@shanghaitech.edu.cn | • Homepage | • GitHub | • Shanghai, China

# Summary

I am a second-year master's student in Computer Science at ShanghaiTech University, supervised by Prof. Xuming He. My research focuses primarily on Computer Vision and Deep Learning, where I concentrate on developing robust structure-prediction models under uncertainty, specializing in areas like learning with noisy labels, uncertainty estimation, and out-of-distribution detection.

# **EDUCATION**

# ShanghaiTech University

Shanghai, China

M.S. in Computer Science, supervised by Prof. Xuming He; Cumulative GPA: 3.86/4.00; Major GPA: 3.94/4.00

Sep. 2021 - Jun. 2024 (Expected)

ShanghaiTech University

Shanghai, China

B.E. in Computer Science; GPA: 3.63/4.0

Sep. 2017 - Jun 2021

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- Zhitong Gao, Yucong Chen, Chuyu Zhang, Xuming He. "Modeling Multimodal Aleatoric Uncertainty in Segmentation with Mixture of Stochastic Experts." International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023. [Paper] [Code]
- Chuanyang Hu, Shipeng Yan, **Zhitong Gao**, Xuming He. "MILD: Modeling the Instance Learning Dynamics for Learning with Noisy Labels." International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJICAI), 2023. [Paper]
- Shuailin Li\*, **Zhitong Gao**\*, Xuming He. "Superpixel-guided Iterative Learning from Noisy Labels for Medical Image Segmentation." International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2021. (\* indicates equal contribution.) [Paper] [Code]

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Dense Out-of-Distribution Detection in the Wild.

Advisor: Xuming He 2022 - Present

- Propose an OOD detection framework for semantic segmentation to effectively detect novel classes in the wild.
- Validate the effectiveness of the proposed method on multiple OOD segmentation benchmarks with simulated situations, demonstrating consistent performance gains.
- In submission.

#### Segmentation of Myocardial Infarction Area from a single T2-STIR MRI image.

Advisor: Xuming He, Lianming Wu

2022 - Present

- Design an automatic cross-modal segmentation system capable of predicting chronic myocardial infarction (MI) regions marked in LGE images based on the corresponding non-enhanced cardiac MRI images. This system needs to cope with the misalignment between the two modalities.
- The proposed model shows satisfactory performance in MI area prediction and provides a calibrated uncertainty score map that facilitates interpreting the reliability of predictions in practice.
- In submission to European Heart Journal.

#### Aleatoric Uncertainty in Segmentation

Advisor: Xuming He 2021 - 2022

- Explicitly model the multimodal characteristic of aleatoric uncertainty in segmentation in a form of mixture of stochastic experts. Each expert encodes a distinct mode and its weight represents the mode probability.
- Formulate the model learning as an Optimal-Transport problem and design a Wasserstein-like loss that directly minimizes the distribution distance between the model and ground truth annotations.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in ICLR 2023.

### Learning Dynamics for noisy labels

Advisor: Xuming He 2021-2022

- Propose a novel selection metric based on the learning dynamics of each data instance. This metric provides a more robust reference for label uncertainty than small-loss trick, as it collects information across various training stages.
- Achieve the state of the art on five popular noisy image classification benchmarks including synthetic noisy datasets and real-world web data.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in IJICAI 2023.

#### Learning with noisy labels in Segmentation

Advisor: Xuming He 2020-2021

- Adopt a superpixel representation and develop a robust iterative learning strategy that combines noise-aware training of segmentation network and noisy label refinement, both guided by the superpixels.
- This design enables us to exploit the structural constraints in segmentation labels and effectively mitigate the impact of label noise in learning.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in MICCAI 2021.

### Workshop and Selected Course Projects

# Bilayer Ensemble Semantic Segmentation for QUBIQ Challenge | Poster

- Quantification of Uncertainties in Biomedical Image Quantification (QUBIQ) Challenge 2021.
- We propose an ensemble of raters, each of whom is trained individually with corresponding experts, thereby enabling them to learn specific characteristics.

#### Generalized DUQ: Generalized Deterministic Uncertainty Quantification | Report

- Final Project of CS282 Machine Learning, ShanghaiTech University
- We proposed an extension to DUQ, called Generalized DUQ, that expands the original uncertainty estimation from using only its nearest centroid, to using the nearest 'k' centroids.

# Seek Common while Shelving Differences: A New Way for dealing with Noisy Labels | Report

- Final Project of CS280 Deep Learning, ShanghaiTech University
- We proposed SCSD, a tri-net framework that combines the benefits of 'cross training' and 'agreement', offering a novel approach to handling noisy labels.

# SKILLS

**Programming:** Python, C, C++, C#, MATLAB, R, Rust, RISC-V

Machine Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Numpy

Miscellaneous: Unity Game Development, Git, ROS, LATEX, Linux

### Relevant Coursework

Deep Learning A+, Computer Vision II A+, Optimization and Machine Learning A+, Online learning and Optimization A+, Natual Language Processing A, Digital Image Analysis A, Probability and Statistics A.